Guide to the Delmer Daves Papers, 1930-1965
Department of Special Collections
- Never Set Me Go (MGM), 1952
  - TLC D. Wright to J. McIntyre (British Museum) re: filming in the British Museum., 6/26/52
  - J. McIntyre to D. Wright TLC re: granting permission to film on Museum steps., 6/9/52
  - TLC D. Wright to Secretary to Royal Corinthian Yacht Club re: asking permission to film on location aththe club., 7/1/52; 2 pgs.
  - Cable D. Schary to DD re: received rushes and is pleased., 7/3/52
  - TLC Joyce M. Dixey to D. Wright re: ballet footage rights for Scheherezade, Sleeping Beauty and Swan Lake., 7/3/52
  - TLS George H. Elvin to DD re: 8 guineas paid., 7/24/52; 6 7/8" × 7 7/8".
  - TNS M. Raymond to DD re: SS Lochavon sailing schedule., 8/22/52
  - TLC M. Raymond to DD re: enpense account and listing summary of DD personal expenses in England., 9/17/52; 5" × 8". 5 pgs.
  - TN Stanley Markham to DD re: DD to be met in N.Y.C. and London with reservations arranges., ND; 8vo.
  - Itinerary for sailing to USA on Queen Mary., ND; 8vo.
  - Personal packing list and check list., ND; 8vo. 7 pgs.
  - Shooting schedule #5 with P sketches and notes., 2/9/52; Legal.
  - Shooting schedule #68with PN., 9/9/52; Legal.
  - Advice of artistss engagementsfor Karl Stepaneek. S., 6/16/52
  - Shooting Schedule for Towan beach sequence., 6/12/52; Legal. 2 copies, 1 C and 1 xerox.
  - Bill from Wallace Heaton Ltd. for development of pictures., 3/31/52; 8vo.
  - Expense accounting at the Dorchester. C., 5/28/52-8/10/72; 2 pgs.
  - Same as #48b with TNS M. Raymond to DD re: enclosure and ANS: answer from DD., 5/28/52-8/10/52
  - Expense sheet for services rendered., ND
  - TLS M. Raymond to DD re: enclosing Doechester bill of 6/17/52., 6/17/52
  - Dorchester billing., 5/27/52
  - Script change to clear up Russian fluency problem., ND
- Folder B: Script
  - Customs that may be carried out at an artistic Russian wedding., ND; Original and carbon. 2 pgs. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - TNS D. Schary to DD re: enclosing #2b., 5/27/52 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - TLC JIB to D. Schary re: censoring Two if By Sea., 5/26/52
  - IOC DD to D. Schary re:notes and comments on 2nd edition rev. script dated 4/30/52., ND; Legal. C. 13 pgs.
  - TL G. R. Webb to M. Raymond re: research on unacceptable propoer names., 5/20/52; Legal. 2 pgs.
  - TCS R. Monta to Clarence Brown re: Unacceptable proper and last names for Denny., 4/29/52
  - Pocket notebook: set drawing, ledger records and production notes., ND; 4 1/4" × 7". Pp. 11 pgs.
- Folder C: Casting Correspondence
  - TLC Lawrence Evans to BG re: unavailability of Alex Guinness for part of Sgt. Denny., 5/2/52; Size X. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - TLS Jules C. Goldstone to DD re: using Yvonne Furneaux., 5/5/52; Size X
  - Cable JJC to BG re: agree to Gene Tierney for part., 5/13/52; 8vo.
  - Cable BG to Bill Grady re: using Bernard Miles for part of Joe., 5/13/52; 8vo.
  - Cable Bill Grady to BG re: agree to Bernard Miles consider John Mills for Denny., 5/14/52; 8vo.
  - TLC Derek J. Glynne to BG re: Bernard Miles contract., 5/19/52; Size X.
  - TLC Derek J. Glynne to BG re: confirmation of #6a., 5/19/52; Size X.
  - TLC Derek J. Glynne to Irene Howard re: terms of Bernard Miles agreement., 5/19/52; Size X.
  - TLC Irene Howard to BG re: using either Naunton Wayne or Nigel Patrick for parts., 5/20/52; Size X.
  - TLC BG to JJC re: shipment #2 of artists' tests., 5/23/52; Size X.
  - IOC Frank R. Clarke to BG re: delivery of shipment #2 of artists' tests., 5/23/52; 8vo.
  - Content sheet for Violetta Elvin test., 5/23/52
  - TLS Mel Ballerino to DD re Characterizing romance of Denny and Svetlana., 5/24/52
  - Cable Bill Grady to BG re using Trevor Howard in part for Denny., 5/26/52; 8vo.
  - Cable DD to Clarence Brown re: urgent casting problems., 5/27/52; 8vo.
  - Cable Grady to BG re: using Richard Haydn?, 5/28/52; 8vo.
  - Cable BG to Bill Grady re: Richard Haydn and Gene Finch., 5/28/52
  - TNC Irene Howard to BG re: possibility of Trevor Howard in part., 5/30/52; 8vo.
  - TLC D. J. Glynne to Irene Howard re: must make Bernard Miles theater schedule coincide with shooting schedule., 5/30/52; 2 pgs.
  - TLC BG to JJC re: actors' tests on film., 5/30/52
  - Cable DD to Clarence Brown re: casting, sent script to Trevor Howard., 6/3/52; 8vo.
  - Cable DD to Clarence Brown re: decision to cast minor parts in hurry., 6/3/52
  - TLC DD to G. H. Elvin re: membership fees andsubscription payments., 7/21/52
  - TLC M. Raymond to George Elvin re: the donation above., 7/21/52
  - TLC W. D. Kelly to BG re: name changes., 8/1/52
  - TLC DD to BG re: extent of possible legal damage from us of certain proper names., 8/5/52; 2 pgs.
  - TLC T. E. Bean to D. Wright re: use of Festival Hall., 8/25/52; 8vo.
  - IOC-S C. Watson to DD re: enclosing letter and documents., 10/29/52
  - List of Characters of Two If By Sea with OpN., 3/52; Size X. (Box 34, Folder 4)
- Never Let me Go
  - Cast list, original plus carbon., ND (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Copies, Advice of Artiste's Engagement including those of Theodore Bickel and Martin Benson., 5/22-9/1/52; 9 pp. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - TNS Irene Howard to DD re: casting Wolf Frees for part., 8/13/52; 8vo. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - TLC Irene Howard to DD re: casting more people for minor parts., 8/20/52; Size X.
  - TLC Irene Howard to DD re: casting for minor parts., 8/19/52; Size X.
  - TLC same as #26e, but different set of actors., 8/19/52
  - TLC same as #26e but different set of actors., 8/15/52
  - Schedule of interviews with DD of Actors with pN on each actor, including Theodore Bickel and Diane Cilento., 5/7/52-5/9/52; 2 pgs. legal, 1 pg. size X. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - T Transcript of #27, C., ND; Legal. 4 pgs. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Diagrams and explanation of Swan Lake ballet with times and explanation of movements. P., ND; Size X. 2 pgs. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Artists' tests #9 - #14. Violetta Elvin. C., 5/22/52; Legal. 4 pgs. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - #406, #407-insert of watch in movie Time Bomb, legal; daily continuity report. C., 5/28/52
  - Artist tests: Peter Finch, Adina Mandlova and A. Mickelson. C., 5/29/52; Legal. 6 pgs.
  - TC test scene for role of Valentina., ND; Legal.
  - Shooting schedule #4. M., 8/15/20; Legal. 2 pgs.
  - T draft for cable re: search for actor for Denny part, and minor details for film., ND; Legal.
- Folder D: General Correspondence
  - ANS Iris Bird to DD re: offering her tchnical assistance on Russian scenes. With envelope., 5/19/[52]; 8vo. 2 pgs. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - TLC F. D. Laughton to Screen Directors' Guild: re waiver for writing credit for Treasure of the Golden Condor., 5/13/52
  - TLS F. D. Laughton to DD re needs letter from DD to [UNK] to authorize waiver., 5/13/52
  - TLS M. Brown (Edgie) to DD re: tracking down an English copyright., 5/15/52; Size X. 2 pgs.
  - TLC DD to Joe Youngerman (Screen Directors' Guild re: authorization of waiver for credit, for Treasure of Golden Condor., 5/27/52; Size X.
  - TLC DD to F. D. Laughton re: waiver of credits and news of personal sight-seeing., 5/27/52; Size X. 2 pgs.
  - TLC Joseph C. Youngerman to DD re: fill out form for compliance and congratulations on new Board post., 5/27/52
  - TLC DD to M. Brown re: personal letter and answer to request of #4 above., 5/28/52; Size X. 2 pgs.
  - TLC DD to J. C. Youngerman re: accepts new board post and encloses non-Communist oath., 6/3/52
    Oath not enclosed
  - List of English towns on driving route northeast of London., ND; Size X.
  - Author's address, see #8 above., ND
  - Formula for Esruscan Gold Granulator. P., ND; 4" × 5 1/2".
- Folder E: London Location
  - TNS R. E. Gray to D. Wright re: confirming appointment to check out Drury Lane Theater., 5/7/52; 8vo. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - TLC David Webster to BG re: making appointment., 5/7/52; Size X.
  - TLC BG to David Webster re: explaining the needs of the movie concerning ballet scenes., 5/12/52; Size X.
  - TLC BG to Prince Littler re: using Drury Lane Theater in picture., 5/12/52; 2 copies C, one with P changes. Size X. 2 pgs. each.
  - TLC BG to Prince Littler re: requirements inusing a theater and requesting its use., 5/19/52; Size X. 2 pgs.
  - TLC David Webster to BG re: can't use company dancers-too busy., 5/20/52; Size X.
  - TLC Prince Littler to BG re: giving permission to use theater., 5/21/52
  - TLC BG to Prince Littler re: schedule of shooting and thanks for permission., 5/23/52; Size X.
  - TLC D. Wright to BG re: itinerary of American Ballet Company., 5/29/52; Size X. 2 pgs.
  - List of American Ballet Company itinerary from D. Wright., 5/27/52; Size X.
  - BG to JJC re: possibility of contracting N.Y.C. Ballet., 5/29/52; 8vo.
  - Cable Bill Grady to BG re: go ahead on negotiations with N.Y.C. Ballet., 5/30/52; 8vo.
  - Draft, TLC of #3 above., ND; Size X. 2 pgs.
  - Draft-relationship of ballet to story and comments on N.Y.C. Ballet. C., ND; Legal. 3 pgs.
  - Ocean Times, published aboard SS Queen Mary, 4/26/52-4/28/52; 11 1/4" × 13 3/4".
  - Tearsheet, article about Never Let Me Go and Clark Gable., 7/13/52; 14 3/8" × 12".
  - Pamphlet on Stonehedge., 1947; 8vo. 4 pgs.
  - Program of events on SS Queen Mary. Printed., 4/26/52 and 4/28/52
  - Mary Martin in South Pacific, program. Printed., ND
- Folder F: Incoming Cables
  - Billy Grady to BG re: asking about characterizations and casting progress., 5/6/52; 8vo. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Billy Grady to BG re: when Gene Tierney needed., 5/9/52; 8vo.
  - JJC to BG re: Clark Gable's wardrobe., 5/9/52; 8vo.
  - JJC to BG re:using Gene Tierney and when absolutely needed., 5/9/52; 8vo.
  - Bill Grady to BG re: Noel Purcell as Joe and Cyril Cusack as Denny., 5/12/52; 8vo.
  - JJC to BG re: electric generators that are available for use., 5/12/52
  - D. Schary to DD re: sending script of Two If By Sea with improvements and additions., 5/14/52; 8vo.
  - JJC to BG re: Gene Tierney's ballet wardrobe., 5/14/52; 8vo.
  - Bill Grady to BG re: casting for Denny part-not David Tomlinson. Nigel Patrick or Cyril Cusack?, 5/16/52; 8vo.
  - Bill Grady to BG re: suggest Naunton Wayne for Denny., 5/18/52; 8vo.
  - Markham to BG re: Gene Tierney's arrival, transportation and housing needs., 5/20/52; 8vo.
  - Floyd Hendrikson to BG re: business details of hiring Clarence Brown., 5/22/52; 8vo.
  - Floyd Hendrickson to BG re: business and passport details for Gene Tierney and living accomodations, etc.., 5/22/52
  - JJC to BG re: hairstyling of Tierney and make-up and wardrobe, character of Denny, casting., 5/26/52
  - JJC to BG re: wigs for Tierney., 5/30/52
  - JJC to BG re: props and wardrobe., 5/30/52
- Folder F: Out Cables
  - BG to JJC re: need generator, some props and asks about wardrobe., 5/9/52
  - BG to JJC re: casting Tierney., 5/12/52
  - BG to JJC re: Tierney's wardrobe for double., 5/15/52; 8vo.
  - BG to JJC re: can do without Tierney up to June 22., 5/13/52; 8vo.
  - BG to D. Schary re: requesting telephone call., 5/16/52; 8vo.
  - DD to D. Schary re: objections to reinsertion of several scenes., 5/16/52
  - BG to JJC re: objections to casting Cusack., 5/19/52; 8vo.
  - BG to Billy Grady re: Naunton Wayne unavailable., 5/21/52; 8vo.
  - DD to D. Schary re: Mailing script review for Dore Schary and Clarence Brown. Confidential., 5/21/52
  - BG to JJC re: John Mills unavailable, Gene Tierney's hairstyle and wardrobe for double., 5/21/52
  - DD to Clarence Brown re: please call., 5/26/52
  - BG to JJC re: need electrical equipment unavailable in England., 5/29/52
- Miscellaneous
  - A. outline of plot. P., ND; 4 1/4" × 7 3/4". 2pgs (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Notes and comments on 2nd edition rev. script of 4/30/52., ND; Carbon and original. Legal. 24 pgs.
  - TLC DD to C. Brown re: using an unknown in a role., [5/6/52]; Size X.
  - TLC DD to C. Brown re: progress report and future plans for shooting., 5/13/52; Size X. 8 pgs.
  - IOC-S R. Monta to C. Brown re: refusal of Life to its mention in movie., 5/13/52
  - Cable D. Schary to DD re: agreement to be made over scripts, 5/16/52; 8vo.
  - IOC F. R. Clarke to BG re: delivery of test scenes to California with Size X content list. C., 5/16/52; 2 pgs.
  - TLC BG to JJC re: sending #1 shipment of test scenes., 5/16/52
  - 2 original draftsoof#22, 5/16/52
  - TLC DD to C. Brown re: production and casting aspects discussed., 5/21/52; Size X. 2pgs
  - TLC W. W. Spencer to BG re: notice of shipment of electrical parts and list and price., 5/22/52; Size X. 2 pgs.
  - TLC JJC to BG re: information on partable recorder., 5/23/52; Size X.
  - Telegram C. Brown to DD re: comments on casting., 5/27/52; 8vo.
  - IOC F. R. Clarke to BG re: notice of #3 shipment of artist tests and container list. C., 5/30/52; 8vo and Size X. 2 pgs.
- Folder G: Location and Production Notes
  - Notes on Cornish location survey with 8 1/2" × 11" sketch of location, [UNK] PN., 5/8/52; 2 copies. M. Legal. 3 pgs. each. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Sets and scene numbers with OPN. M., 5/5/52; Legal. 4 pgs.
  - General notes for guidance in pre-planning production work to be done in Cornwall. M., 5/15/52; Legal. 10 pgs. 2 copies
  - P drawing of set with note., ND; 4 1/4" × 7 3/4".
  - New Quay, Mevagissey and Mullion pre-location report. M., 5/26/52; Legal. 5 pgs.
  - Exterior shooting schedule., 5/19/52; 2 copies, M and C. Legal. 2 pgs. each.
  - Photocopy of sequence schdeul #1 and #2., ND; 13" × 20".
  - Shooting Schedule 1A pgs. 3-5. M., 5/30/52; Legal. 3 pgs.
  - Schedule for Cornish location set with hotel accomodations. M., 6/4/52; Legal. 2 pgs. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - List of notes for cast and crew at 3 locations., ND; 4 pgs
  - Notes on actor and actress interviews., 5/7,9/52; Legal. 4 pgs.
  - Sketches and PN., ND; 4 1/4# × 7 3/4". 11 pgs.
  - P and T notes., ND; 8vo. 3 pgs.
  - Shooting schedule #2 with 4 pgs P sketches on vso. of inserts showing England, North Sea and English Channel. M., 7/21/52; Legal. 4 pgs.
  - TNS M. Raymond to DD and list of expenses (Size X) re: personal expense account., 7/30/52; 2 pgs.
  - Expense sheet. C., ND; 15" × 13". 10 pgs.
  - List of cash advances to DD with A. balance to be credited., ND; 7" × 8".
  - Exterior shooting schedule-time needed to film., 4/29/52; Legal. 4 pgs.
  - Rough notes on production with PN., 5/9/52; 4 pgs.
  - PN, front and vso., ND
  - Artist's set test for Diane Cilento., 5/15/52; Legal.
  - Tests #1-#8. C., 5/15/52; Legal. 10 pgs.
  - Daily diary. C., 5/15/52
  - The Bondon Times tearsheet-folio., 8/6/52
  - London Evening News re: Russian Capture of yacht., 8/13/52
  - LA Herald and Express re: Gen. MacArthur., 6/8/52
- Folder H: Correspondence, Cables
  - BG to JJC re: assembling add sending off electric generator., 5/14/52; 8vo. (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - BG to JJC re: casting and wardrobe, 5/14/52
  - DD to D. Schary re: refusal to work with script in which withdrawn scenes reinstated., 5/15/52
  - BG to Gil Cote, N.C.C. re: arrival of Mrs. Daves in N.Y.C.., 6/3/52; 8vo.
  - BG to Kelly re: proper name clearance., 6/3/52
  - BG to Kelly re: proper name clearance., 6/4/52; 8vo.
  - Kelly to BG re: check proper names., 6/4/52; 8vo.
  - JJC to BG re: doubles' wardrobe shipment awaiting import license., 6/5/52; 8vo.
  - Bill Grady to BG re: needdcast results immediately., 6/5/52; 8vo.
  - BG to E. J. Mannix re: Clark Gable's arrival and screen tests., 6/5/52; 8vo.
  - BG to Bill Grady re: information on production., 6/5/52; 8vo.
  - BG to JJC re: need information to get import license for wardrobes., 6/5/52; 8vo.
  - BG to JJC re: casting parts., 6/6/52
- Letters
  - TLS Edward Lawrence, studio publicity, to DD re: publicity for the movie., 5/2/52
  - TLC JJC to BG re: use of stock Russian newsreel., 5/12/52
  - TLC Prince Littler to BG re: using Drury Lane Theater., 5/14/52; Size X.
  - IOC-S Alfred Junge, art director, to D. Wright re: research on lighthouses and buoys., 5/16/52; 8vo with 3 pgs Size X. C. 4 pgs.
  - TLS Howard Strickling, dir. of studio publicity, to DD re: request information on film for publicity purposes., 5/19/52
  - TLC D. Wright to Corp. of Trinity House, Secretary re: use of lighthouse., 5/22/52; Size X. 3 pgs.
  - TLC W. D. Kelly to BG re: proper name clearance., 5/23/52
  - TLC W. D. Kelly to BG re: title., 5/27/52
  - TLC D. Wright to Mevagissey Harbour Trustees re: thanks for permission to use harbour., 5/30/52; Size X.
  - TLC E. Hankin, Mebagissey Harbour Trastees, to D. Wright re: permission to use harbour granted., 5/28/52
  - TLC L. Sheridan to D. Wright re: terms for filming on cliffs and beach., 5/28/52
  - TLC D. Wright to Lt. Col. Leslie Sheridan, National Trust re: enclosing check to pay for use of beaches, etc., 5/30/52
  - TLC W. D. Kelly to BG re: using trade names in script., 6/2/52; Size X.
  - TL copy G. R. Webb to M. Raymond re: using proper names., 6/3/52; Size X.
  - TLC D. Wright to M. Raymond re: possible use of London Festival Ballet., 7/24/52
  - TLS Spink and Son, Ltd. to DD re: information for Dave's son on war medal collection., 8/22/52
- Folder I: Dress Charts
  - Cable BG to JJC re: need duplication of Tierney ballet costume., 5/26/52 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Costume breakdown for Gene Tierney with PN., ND; Size 1X. 2 pgs.
  - TLC JJC to BG re: enclosing requested information., 5/19/52; Size X.
  - TLS Sam Kress to BG re: costume production., 5/19/52
  - Time lapse of movie story and scenes to be tested, with PN., 5/5/52; Size 1X
  - Dress charts for all parts., 5/1/52; Legal. 20 pgs.
- Folder J: Scripts
  - Never Let Me Go- SP by Ronald Millar and George Froeschel, rev. by DD., 4/10/52; Legal. 122 pgs. (Box 35, Folder 9)
    Box 35 ends here
  - Temp. complete script rev. by DD., 4/22/52; 116 pgs. (Box 34, Folder 12)
    Box 34 continues (From p. 98)
    Box 34 continuation
  - Temp. complete script., 3/22/52; ca. 100 pgs. M. (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Complete script by Millar and Froeschel with general comments and points of value by DD., 3/13/52; ca. 100 pgs. (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Temp. complete script with F sketches and PN on pages., 1/28/52; 128 pgs. (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Continuity outline by Roger Bax- Two If By Sea. M., ND; 17 pgs. (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Excerpts from #3 above;with PN and sketches. 10 pgs., 3/22/52
- Lord Vanity (20CF-never used), 1954
  - BW wardrobe and make-up test photos of A. Alberghetti, Robert Wagner and Clifton WEbb., 10/14/54; 8 1/2" × 10". 10 items. (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - 3 color translucent photographs of Alberghetti (2) and Wagner (1)., 10/14/54; 1/2" × 10".
  - #2 Lord Vanity- overseas process shots and breakdown with OpN and 70 BW 8" × 10" photos., 50 pgs. (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Photos (Box 34, Folder 19-21)
  - Final script and pre-productionwork abroad and reasch notes; SP by Charles Brackett and Walter Reisch from novel by Samuel Shellabarger (cancelled by DFZ), with set floor plans (40 pgs.) andcameta breakdowns. T and M., 11/1/54; ca. 300 pgs. (Box 34, Folder 22)
    192/34/22 - Final Script, 126pp Box 34 ends here, Box 36 begins (Box 35 is pp. 98-106)
  - TLX Grantie to DD re: personal., 3/1/44 (Box 36, Folder 1, Folder 2)
  - Subscription form for American Magazine of Art., ND (Box 36, Folder 3)
- White Feather (20CF), 1954
  - Folder A: Correspondence
    - TLC DFZ to Louis Lighton re: My Great- Aunt Appearing Day (treatment of 3/30/53)-first continuity with outlines. M., 4/14/53; 6 pgs. (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - IOC-S David Brown to DD with enclosure re: short story by John Prebble and treatment by L. Lighton with comments by DFZ., 12/16/53; 8vo.
    - Enclosure of #2a above., 4/14/53
    - IOC DD to DFZ re: comments on items in #2. C., 12/17/53; 7 pgs.
    - Report on treatment by DD, S. C. (same as #3)., ND
    - IOC DFZ to DD re: further comments., 1/11/54
    - Typescript copy of My Great-Aunt Appearing Day by John Preblle., 11/3/52; 54 pgs. (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Carbon screen treatment by Buddy Lighton. 99 pgs. Found it., 3/30/53 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Screen treatment (signed) by DD with FPNAD. 85 pgs. WHITE Feather, ND (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - First draft screenplay by DD - titled White Feather, 1954; 122 pgs. (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Final Draft Screenplay for White Feather M., 7/1/54; 111 pgs. (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Breakdown and notes by DD with FPNAD., ND; 7 pgs. (Box 36, Folder 10)
- The Robe (20CF), 1954
  - Rev Final SP by DD, 11/11/52; 157 pgs. (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Photos of single pages containing story-board sketches (1 to 3 per page)., ND; total. 181 pages (Box 36, Folder 12-14)
    Original non-numerica order retained
    - PAGES 1-50 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - 51-99 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - 100-149 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - 150-181 (Box 37, Folder 1)
- Demetrius and the Gladiators (20CF), 1954
  - The Story of Demetrius - writer's working script with general comments, 1/9/53; 42 pgs. (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - General comments on script so far and hopes for the future. C., ND; 7 pgs.
  - Outline - Story of Demotrius. C., ND; 3 pgs.
  - Prologue to Story of Demetrius. C., 6 pgs.
  - IOC copy DD to Frank Ross re:first 40 pgs. of Demetrius story., ND; 2 pgs.
  - IOC copy DD to Frank Ross re: working script to pg. 40., ND; 3 pgs.
  - SP by Phillip Dunne-writer's working script with FPNAD by DD., 1/23/53; 127 pgs. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - 2nd writer's working scrip with FPNAD by DD., 4/1/53; 130 pgs. (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Reasearch notes., ND; ca. 70 pgs. C. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Same as #2 with Sew added set sketches and scenes., 2/26/53; ca. 150 pgs. (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Fina script., 5/20/53; 125 pgs. (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Temporary Script, 4/20/53; 125 pgs. (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Research notes on Roman times and script., ND; ca. 100 pgs. (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - General comments on script so far and hopes for the future. C., ND; 7 pgs. (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Continuity outline, Story of Demetrius., ND; 3 pgs.
  - Notes on advantages and disadvantages of the wide screen of cinemascope, with OPN., ND; 10 pgs.
  - Notes from conference on 2nd working script of 4/1/53. MM to DD. M., 4/7/53; 9 pgs.
  - Script sequence breakdown., ND; 23 pgs.
  - From Frank Ross-sequence by sequence step outline., 1/53; 4 pgs. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - List of characters in script., ND; 2 pgs. C. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - A. Music score for Gloria in Excelsis. P., ND (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Parts of script and misc. notes on script with changes and additions., ND; 18 pgs (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - IOC DD to DFZ re: work report, progress in script revisions and statement that he had part in script writing. C., 3/9/53 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - IOC DD to Frank Ross re: hiring sword fighting doubles. C., 5/7/53 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - IOC DD to Charles LeMaire re: casting Ann Bancroft and Debra Paget., 5/11/53; 8vo.
  - TLS Lay E. Kuter to DD re: asking for personal interview., 5/11/53
  - DFZ to DD re: likes first rushed., 5/29/53; 8vo.
  - TLS William J. Fadiman to DD re: compliments on good trade reviews., 6/2/53; 8vo.
  - TOC-SIB to Frank McCarthy re: changes in script., 6/3/53
  - IOC-S Frank McCarthy to DD re: enclosing memo on violence and brutality in films by British film board., 5/28/53; 2 pgs.
  - IOC copy DFZ to Frank Ross re: uses of cinemascope in shooting angles., 6/3/53
  - IOC DFZ to Frank Ross re: compliments on excellent rushes., 6/10/53; 8vo. C.
  - IOC DFZ to Frank Ross re: compliments on rushes., 6/12/53
  - DFZ to Frank Ross re: comments on Debra Paget's hair style., 6/16/53; 8vo.
  - IOC DFZ to Frank Ross re: enthusiasm of rushes., 6/27/53; 8vo.
  - IOC DFZ to F. Ross re: enthusiasm on rushes., 7/2/53; 8vo.
  - IOC DFZ to F. Ross re: enthusiasm on rushes., 7/3/53; 8vo.
  - DFZ to F. Ross re: enthusiasm on rushes-IOC., 7/10/53; 8vo.
  - IOC to DFZ re: filming and censorship, with the following enclosures:, 8/19/53
  - memMemo by E.G.D. (?) re: film., 5/6/53
- Demetrius and the Gladiators 2